Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我的名字是马可。
And my name is Catherine and today we have an exciting lesson for everyone out there,
我叫Catherine，今天我们要为大家带来一堂非常精彩的课程。
very cultural.
很有文化气息。
Exactly, very closely related to our Halloween lesson that we had but on this occasion we're
没错，和我们之前那节万圣节课程非常相关，但这次我们
going to be looking at All Saints Day.
我们将要探讨的是万圣节。
Alright, so this is a festival that's celebrated in many different countries and we're learning
好的，这是一个在许多不同国家都会庆祝的节日，我们正在了解它。
today about some of the ceremonies and practices in those countries that are very closely tied
今天我们来聊聊这些国家中一些与仪式和习俗紧密相关的内容。
to those local cultures.
对于这些当地文化。
Exactly, so we're going to learn a little bit about culture and at the same time we're
没错，所以我们要学一点文化知识，同时我们也要
going to learn some great words and phrases.
我们将学习一些很棒的单词和短语。
So let's get started with this dialogue for the first time.
那么，让我们第一次开始这段对话吧。
The day of the dead has arrived.
亡灵节到了。
All souls day and all saints day.
万灵节和万圣节。
Your neighbor is crazy.
你的邻居疯了。
Why is he screaming that?
他为什么那样大喊大叫？
Because today is the first of November, the day of the dead.
因为今天是11月1日，亡灵节。
Oh, that's right.
哦，没错。
This is a very special day among many cultures around the world, especially in Latin America.
这是一个在许多文化中都非常特别的日子，尤其是在拉丁美洲。
Seriously?
真的假的？
I thought it was just like any other day except for the fact that people visit the cemetery
我以为这只是普通的一天，只不过人们会去扫墓。
and remember their loved ones.
并且记住他们的亲人。
Well that's just part of it.
嗯，那只是其中一部分。
People across the world celebrate in different ways.
世界各地的人们以不同的方式庆祝。
In Mexico for example it's common to see people building private altars honoring the deceased,
例如在墨西哥，人们通常会搭建私人祭坛来纪念逝者。
using sugar skulls, preparing the favorite foods and beverages of the departed and visiting
用糖骷髅头、准备逝者生前最爱的食物和饮品，以及去扫墓。
graves with these as gifts.
用这些作为礼物来陪葬。
In the Philippines the tombs are cleaned or repainted.
在菲律宾，人们会清理或重新粉刷坟墓。
Candles are lit and flowers are offered.
蜡烛被点燃，鲜花被献上。
Entire families camp out in cemeteries and sometimes spend a night or two near the relative's
整个家庭会在墓地里露营，有时会在亲人旁边待上一两个晚上。
tombs.
坟墓。
Whoa, that's scary.
哇，那可真吓人。
I don't know if I could do that.
我不知道我能不能做到。
Why?
为什么？
We should fear the living, not the dead.
我们应该害怕活人，而不是死人。
And we're back, so did you know about these traditions in the Philippines and in Mexico?
我们回来了，那么你之前知道菲律宾和墨西哥的这些传统吗？
I know about the Mexican ones because there's a lot of Mexicans where I come from in Chicago
我知道墨西哥卷饼，因为在我老家芝加哥有很多墨西哥人。
and they still celebrate these things.
而且他们至今还在庆祝这些事。
But I didn't know about the Philippines so I found this really interesting.
但我对菲律宾不太了解，所以觉得这特别有意思。
Interesting, right?
有意思，对吧？
Actually, yeah, the Philippines as well as Mexico are very Catholic countries so maybe
实际上，是的，菲律宾和墨西哥都是非常天主教的国家，所以也许
that's one of the reasons why they have these events that are so important for their culture.
这就是为什么他们举办这些活动的原因之一，这些活动对他们的文化非常重要。
I'm sure, yeah.
我确定，是的。
All right, so before we start talking a little bit more about the culture, why don't we take
好的，在我们开始多聊一点文化之前，不如我们先来
a look at language takeaway.
语言要点部分。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
All right, the first word is a very common word especially if you're a church-going person.
好的，第一个词是一个非常常见的词，尤其是如果你经常去教堂的话。
The word is altar.
这个词是“祭坛”。
Okay, an altar.
好的，一个祭坛。
An altar, it's a thing.
祭坛，就是那个东西。
It's a thing and an altar is usually found inside a church as you said, right?
这个东西，而且祭坛通常是在教堂里面的，对吧？就像你说的那样。
That's right.
没错。
So it's like a...
所以它就像是一个……
Table.
桌子。
It's like a table.
它就像一张桌子。
Or a counter.
或者是一个柜台。
So the altar in the church is where the priest does all of the stuff that he does during
所以教堂里的祭坛就是神父做所有那些他在弥撒中做的事情的地方。
the mass.
质量。
It's where he prepares the bread and the wine and it's essentially a table, yeah.
那是他准备面包和葡萄酒的地方，基本上就是一张桌子，没错。
But you can build an altar for yourself in your garden, for example, right?
但你可以在自己的花园里建一个祭坛，对吧？
And it doesn't have to do with the Catholic religion necessarily.
而且这不一定与天主教有关。
No, not necessarily.
不，不一定。
You could have an altar in a Greek pagan temple where you give offerings to a god or goddess.
你可以在希腊异教神庙里设一个祭坛，向某位神祇或女神献祭。
So in this case, an altar is a special religious table where you perform certain religious
所以在这种情况下，祭坛是一张特殊的宗教桌子，你在上面进行某些宗教仪式。
rites or functions.
仪式或功能。
Okay, very interesting.
好的，非常有趣。
All right, and so it's common in Mexico for people to build private altars honoring the
好的，在墨西哥，人们通常会搭建私人祭坛来纪念
deceased.
去世了。
So what is this word, deceased?
那这个词“deceased”是什么意思？
All right, deceased is a noun.
好的，"deceased" 是一个名词。
It's a word that we use to call someone who's dead or departed.
这是一个用来称呼已故或逝去之人的词。
So the deceased was named John Smith.
所以死者名叫约翰·史密斯。
So it's like a more technical term of saying somebody is dead.
所以这算是说某人死了的一个更专业的说法。
Right, and it's something that you'll often read in the newspaper when they don't want
对，而且这是你经常在报纸上看到的，当他们不想（直接说）的时候。
to say the dead guy.
说那个死人。
The deceased was a doctor and he is survived by three children.
死者是一名医生，留下了三个孩子。
And so deceased is a way to describe a person in a nicer way.
所以"deceased"是一种更礼貌地描述逝者的方式。
Right, very good, the deceased.
好的，非常好，死者。
And you mentioned another word that's very closely related to deceased, the departed.
你还提到了另一个与“deceased”密切相关的词，就是“the departed”。
That's right, and this is actually a famous word because of a Martin Scorsese movie that
没错，而且这个词因为马丁·斯科塞斯的一部电影而变得非常有名。
came out about two years ago.
大约两年前出版的。
And departed, you know the word to depart, to leave.
而“departed”，你知道这个词，意思是离开、离去。
A person that is a departed is someone who has left us.
“departed”指的是已经离开我们的人。
It's a dead person.
也就是去世的人。
So you can say the deceased or the departed, which basically means the same thing as the
所以你可以说“the deceased”或“the departed”，基本上和
dead guy or the dead person.
“死掉的人”或“死者”意思相同。
Exactly, but again, it's much more polite.
没错，但再次强调，这样更礼貌。
It's something that we hear often at funerals or that we read in magazines.
这是我们在葬礼上常听到的，或者在杂志上读到的。
Okay, so for example, All Saints Day is a way of honoring the departed.
好的，比如，万圣节是纪念逝者的一种方式。
Exactly, very nice sounding.
没错，听起来很悦耳。
Yeah, it sounds better.
是啊，听起来更好。
All right, so talking a little bit more about the departed and the traditions, it says here
好了，再聊聊逝者和传统，这里提到
that many Mexicans use sugar skulls or have sugar skulls during this festivity.
许多墨西哥人在这个节日里使用糖骷髅或拥有糖骷髅。
That's right.
没错。
So a skull is the bones from a person's head.
所以“skull”指的是人头部的骨头。
And so you can often see these on, for example, pirate ships.
你经常能在比如海盗船上看到这些。
We say skull and crossbones.
我们称之为骷髅和交叉骨。
And so it's the bones from a head and you have the bones underneath.
就是头部的骨头，下面还有骨头。
It's a very popular image on Halloween because it's scary.
这是万圣节很流行的形象，因为它很吓人。
But a skull is essentially the bones from a head.
但“skull”本质上就是头部的骨头。
So it's like a person's head without the skin, eyes, lips, everything.
就像一个人的头，没有皮肤、眼睛、嘴唇等等。
Right, it's scary because it has empty black spaces where the eyes are supposed to be and
对，它吓人是因为眼睛位置有空洞的黑色空间，
you can see all the teeth, but nothing else.
你能看到所有牙齿，但其他什么都没有。
What about the sugar skulls?
那糖骷髅呢？
What are these?
那是什么？
They're skulls made of sugar.
是用糖做的骷髅。
That's right.
没错。
And so they look like skulls because there's no cheeks and there's no skin or eyes, but
它们看起来像骷髅，因为没有脸颊、皮肤或眼睛，但
they're beautiful because the Mexicans in their tradition, they color the sugar.
它们很漂亮，因为墨西哥人在传统中会给糖上色。
So you can have white skulls with this beautiful green and pink and red and blue decorations
所以你可以有白色骷髅，配上漂亮的绿色、粉色、红色和蓝色装饰，
and you can eat them because they're made of sugar.
而且你可以吃它们，因为它们是用糖做的。
And so it's a special treat that people have in the Mexican tradition on the Day of the
所以这是墨西哥传统中在亡灵节
Dead.
的一种特别美食。
Very good.
非常好。
And one of the many traditions apart from sugar skulls and building private altars,
除了糖骷髅和搭建私人祭坛之外，许多传统之一，
they also visit the person's tomb, if possible, right?
他们还会在可能的情况下拜访逝者的坟墓，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
So a tomb is an important word.
所以“tomb”是一个重要的词。
So what is a tomb?
那么什么是“tomb”？
A tomb is a place where someone is buried.
“tomb”是埋葬某人的地方。
It's a space or a place and it can be big or small, but it's essentially the resting
它是一个空间或地方，可大可小，但本质上是死者的安息
place of a dead person.
之所。
All right.
好的。
So a tomb, where the person is.
所以是坟墓，死者所在的地方。
And actually on the tomb, you have the tombstone, right?
实际上在坟墓上，还有墓碑，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
And a tombstone is the same as a gravestone and it's a piece of rock on which you write
墓碑和墓石是一样的，是一块石头，上面刻着
the name and the birth date and the death date of the person that is buried there.
埋葬在那里的人的名字、出生日期和死亡日期。
Right.
对。
So that's the tombstone.
那就是墓碑。
Very good.
非常好。
Okay.
好的。
So an interesting amount of words here on Language Takeaway.
在“语言小贴士”部分，我们有不少有趣的词汇。
Why don't we listen to this dialogue again and we'll be right back with Fluency Builder.
我们不如再听一遍这段对话，然后马上回来进入“流利度训练”。
Your neighbor is crazy.
你的邻居疯了。
Why is he screaming that?
他为什么那样喊？
Because today is the first of November, the Day of the Dead.
因为今天是11月1日，亡灵节。
Oh, that's right.
哦，对。
This is a very special day among many cultures around the world, especially in Latin America.
这在世界各地的许多文化中都是非常特殊的一天，尤其是在拉丁美洲。
Seriously?
真的吗？
I thought it was just like any other day, except for the fact that people visit the
我以为它和其他日子没什么两样，除了人们会去
cemetery and remember their loved ones.
墓地缅怀亲人。
Well, that's just part of it.
嗯，那只是其中一部分。
People across the world celebrate in different ways.
世界各地的人们以不同的方式庆祝。
In Mexico, for example, it's common to see people building private altars honoring the
例如，在墨西哥，常见人们搭建私人祭坛来纪念
deceased, using sugar skulls, preparing the favorite foods and beverages of the departed
逝者，使用糖骷髅，准备逝者生前最喜欢的食物和饮料，
and visiting graves with these as gifts.
并带着这些作为礼物去扫墓。
In the Philippines, the tombs are cleaned or repainted.
在菲律宾，人们会清理或重新粉刷坟墓。
Candles are lit and flowers are offered.
点燃蜡烛，献上鲜花。
Entire families camp out in cemeteries and sometimes spend a night or two near the relatives'
整个家庭会在墓地露营，有时会在亲人
tombs.
坟墓旁住上一两晚。
Whoa, that's scary.
哇，那太吓人了。
I don't know if I could do that.
我不知道我能不能做到。
Why?
为什么？
We should fear the living, not the dead.
我们应该害怕活人，而不是死人。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So why don't we look at three main phrases on Fluency Builder now?
那么，我们现在来看看“流利度训练”中的三个主要短语吧？
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
Well, the first phrase should be obvious by now because it is the name of the holiday
嗯，第一个短语现在应该很明显了，因为它就是我们正在谈论的节日的名字，
we're talking about and the name is the Day of the Dead.
叫做“亡灵节”。
The Day of the Dead.
亡灵节。
So this is their day.
所以这是他们的日子。
It is and it's the Day of the Dead because it's the day in which people around the world
是的，它叫亡灵节，因为在这一天，世界各地的人们
celebrate the departed.
庆祝逝者。
It's when they talk about and remember people that they've loved who've died.
这是他们谈论和怀念他们爱过并已故之人的时候。
Okay.
好的。
So it's not really like a sad day, right?
所以这其实不是一个悲伤的日子，对吧？
It's more of a happy remembering them and honoring them and how much you miss them,
更多的是快乐地怀念他们、纪念他们，表达你有多想念他们，
but in a good way.
但以一种积极的方式。
Exactly.
正是如此。
And you're not actually going to hear this very often in reference to American culture
而且你很少会在美国文化中听到这个说法，
because it's not something Americans do and English people don't do either.
因为这不是美国人会做的事，英国人也不会。
But people, when they're talking about their own families and traditions, will want to
但是，当人们谈论自己的家庭和传统时，他们会想
talk about this because in the Philippines or in Latin America, you have a very strong
谈论这个，因为在菲律宾或拉丁美洲，有非常浓厚的
culture, like a very strong tradition of celebrating this.
文化，也就是非常浓厚的庆祝这个节日的传统。
So.
所以。
All right.
好的。
And as we mentioned, this day is a day to honor or to remember your loved ones.
正如我们提到的，这一天是为了纪念或缅怀你的亲人。
And that's our second phrase, your loved ones.
那是我们的第二个短语，“你的亲人”。
The phrase loved ones might not be obvious to many people because you can love many people
“亲人”这个短语对很多人来说可能不太明显，因为你可以爱很多人
and many things, but loved ones is a phrase that generally means the people that you care
和很多东西，但“亲人”通常指的是你最关心的人，
about the most, your friends and your family.
你的朋友和家人。
So you could say, I want to have a party, but I only want my loved ones to be there.
所以你可以说，我想办个派对，但我只想让我的亲人在场。
Okay.
好的。
Or he was in the hospital and all of his loved ones visited him.
或者，他住院了，他所有的亲人都去看望了他。
So all those people, not necessarily only family, it's friends and family that you love.
所以是那些人，不一定只是家人，而是你爱的朋友和家人。
Exactly.
正是如此。
And so those are the people in the world that are the very closest to you.
所以他们是世界上与你最亲近的人。
Okay.
好的。
And our last phrase and probably one of the most interesting traditions that we were able
我们的最后一个短语，可能也是我们在对话中看到的最有趣的
to see in this dialogue is that people in the Philippines camp out in cemeteries on
传统之一，就是菲律宾人在
their family or loved ones tomb.
家人或亲人的坟墓旁露营。
That's right.
没错。
So the phrase to camp out means to stay overnight to bring food and a tent or blankets.
所以“露营”这个短语意味着过夜，带上食物、帐篷或毯子。
And it essentially means to make a camp so you can stay there.
它本质上意味着搭建一个营地，以便你能待在那里。
And this is very unusual to me because I can't imagine sleeping in a graveyard.
这对我来说非常不寻常，因为我无法想象睡在墓地里。
I think I get the goosebumps.
我想我会起鸡皮疙瘩。
Right.
对。
So camp out or you can just say camp, right?
所以“camp out”或者你直接说“camp”，对吧？
You don't necessarily have to say both of them.
你不一定非要说两个词。
Right.
对。
You can camp or you can camp out and camp out generally means that you're staying in
你可以说“camp”或“camp out”，而“camp out”通常意味着你待在一个
a place that is temporary.
临时的地方。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So interesting phrases as well on Fluency Builder today.
今天的“流利度训练”中也有有趣的短语。
Let's listen to the dialogue for the last time and we'll be right back.
让我们最后再听一遍对话，然后马上回来。
The Day of the Dead has arrived.
亡灵节到了。
All souls day and all saints day.
万灵节和万圣节。
Your neighbor is crazy.
你的邻居疯了。
Why is he screaming that?
他为什么那样喊？
Because today is the first of November, the Day of the Dead.
因为今天是11月1日，亡灵节。
Oh, that's right.
哦，对。
This is a very special day among many cultures around the world, especially in Latin America.
这在世界各地的许多文化中都是非常特殊的一天，尤其是在拉丁美洲。
Seriously?
真的吗？
I thought it was just like any other day, except for the fact that people visit the
我以为它和其他日子没什么两样，除了人们会去
cemetery and remember their loved ones.
墓地缅怀亲人。
Well, that's just part of it.
嗯，那只是其中一部分。
People across the world celebrate in different ways.
世界各地的人们以不同的方式庆祝。
In Mexico, for example, it's common to see people building private altars honoring the
例如，在墨西哥，常见人们搭建私人祭坛来纪念
deceased, using sugar skulls, preparing the favorite foods and beverages of the departed
逝者，使用糖骷髅，准备逝者生前最喜欢的食物和饮料，
and visiting graves with these as gifts.
并带着这些作为礼物去扫墓。
In the Philippines, the tombs are cleaned or repainted.
在菲律宾，人们会清理或重新粉刷坟墓。
Candles are lit and flowers are offered.
点燃蜡烛，献上鲜花。
Entire families camp out in cemeteries and sometimes spend a night or two near the relatives'
整个家庭会在墓地露营，有时会在亲人
tombs.
坟墓旁住上一两晚。
Oh, that's scary.
哦，那太吓人了。
I don't know if I could do that.
我不知道我能不能做到。
Why?
为什么？
We should fear the living, not the dead.
我们应该害怕活人，而不是死人。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So, Catherine, you mentioned that in Anglo-Saxon culture, England or in the United States,
那么，凯瑟琳，你提到在盎格鲁-撒克逊文化中，英国或美国，
you don't have this type of tradition of honoring the dead or something like that, but you
没有这种纪念死者的传统，但你们也会
do visit the tomb of your loved ones or the cemetery as well, right?
去亲人的坟墓或墓地，对吧？
People do, definitely.
人们确实会去，毫无疑问。
But you just don't have a national day where you do this.
但你们没有一个全国性的日子来做这件事。
Well, Veterans Day is a day when we celebrate people who were killed in wars or people who
嗯，退伍军人节是我们庆祝在战争中牺牲或参与战争的人的日子。
participated in wars.
So in America, we have a day called Memorial Day in which we remember the people who have
所以在美国，我们有一个叫阵亡将士纪念日的日子，我们纪念那些
died serving the country in the military.
在军队中为国捐躯的人。
And so Memorial Day is a day in which many people like to go to the graveyards and to
所以阵亡将士纪念日是一个很多人喜欢去墓地
lay flowers or to remember the dead.
献花或缅怀逝者的日子。
But it really depends on your family.
但这真的取决于你的家庭。
I mean, some people like to go the day a person died and on the anniversary or on a
我的意思是，有些人喜欢在逝者去世的那天、周年纪念日或
special day for them.
对他们来说特别的日子去。
So it's very private and personal and individual.
所以这非常私密、个人化且因人而异。
It's not something that we all do on one particular day.
这不是我们在某一天统一做的事情。
And I think what may strike many people as different is that you visit the cemetery and
我认为可能让很多人觉得不同的是，你去墓地时，
if you ever have the chance to be in Mexico or in a Hispanic country, you will see that
如果你有机会去墨西哥或一个西班牙语国家，你会看到
it's full of people and it's actually a, there's a lot of food and people are there eating
那里人山人海，而且实际上有很多食物，人们就在
on the tomb and just, and they've actually prepared the food that was the deceased's
墓前吃东西，他们准备的食物正是逝者生前
favorite.
最喜欢的。
Wow, that's really nice though as a gesture because it's another way to remember the person
哇，这作为心意真的很不错，因为这是另一种记住那个人
and to celebrate how, how, like things that were happy for them.
并庆祝那些对他们来说快乐的事情的方式。
Exactly.
没错。
And it's a way of actually sharing a meal with that person even though that person isn't
而且这实际上是一种与那个人共享一顿饭的方式，即使那个人
with you anymore in this world.
已经不在这个世界上了。
So yeah, it's actually very interesting.
所以是的，这真的很有趣。
It goes back again to a little bit of the culture and the folklore and everything from
这又回到了不同国家的文化、民间传说
different countries.
以及一切相关的东西。
And we want to know what you guys do or how you remember your deceased because each country
我们想知道你们是怎么做的，或者你们如何纪念逝者，因为每个国家
has its own particular little very interesting way of doing it.
都有自己独特且非常有趣的方式。
That's right.
没错。
So please share with us on our website EnglishPod.com your own traditions and the culture that you
所以请在我们的网站 EnglishPod.com 上与我们分享你们自己的传统，
have in your home country or town.
以及你们祖国或家乡的文化。
And we're very curious to hear those.
我们非常好奇想听听这些。
But also if you have questions as always, please ask because we're happy to answer those.
但如果你有问题，也请随时提问，因为我们很乐意回答。
All right.
好的。
So we'll see you guys there.
那我们到时候见。
Bye everyone.
大家再见。
Bye, bye.
再见。